<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>/findings/context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/context/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 COVID-19 has affected all parts of life and we are interested in how it has impacted Emergency Medical Services in Charlottesville and the larger Albermarle County. Counterintuitively, we can observe that there is a significant drop off in call volume to emergency medical services. This may be caused by people staying at home more and thus there being less emergency incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response Time Analysis</title>
      <link>/findings/response-time-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/response-time-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Model Results 
For more details on the specification of our model, see the Data &amp;amp; Methods tab.

Measures of Model Fit We assessed the specification of our model using a posterior predictive check, which is common in Bayesian estimation. The posterior predictive check compares the distribution of predicted response times for each MCMC draw (I think this needs a very brief elaboration – people may not know what is being drawn exactly) to the actual distribution of response times in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Symptoms</title>
      <link>/findings/covid-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/covid-indicator/</guid>
      <description>Background While we were obviously interested in identifying patterns in COVID-19 symptoms across demographic groups, time, and space, this portion of the project was also quite exploratory, as it was unclear how difficult it might be to isolate potential COVID-19 cases in a large EMS dataset.
According to the Johns Hopkins Center for Systems Science and Engineering, as of June 9, 2020 (the most current date in our data), there were 258 confirmed cases and 8 deaths in Albemarle County, and 141 confirmed cases and 3 deaths in Charlottesville City.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>