<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Findings on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/findings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Findings on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/findings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Symposium Presentation</title>
      <link>/findings/symposium_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/symposium_page/</guid>
      <description>While this page is optional, it probably makes sense to have one weighted at the top (see the front matter at the top of this Rmd file) that gives a general overview of the project. This could be something like the final poster while the other pages highlight more in-depth observations. Here is a general schema of what should be covered throughout your website:
Main Findings [Here you will describe the results and include important visualizations from your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>/findings/context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/context/</guid>
      <description>Demographics Given this project&#39;s focus on health equity, we first wanted to develop a better understanding of the demographic makeup of Charlottesville and Albemarle. While this information is readily available from the American Community Survey (ACS), census tracts and block groups often don&#39;t present an accurate representation of the population distribution in a town or city. We therefore used data from the ACS in Charlottesville to estimate the demographic makeup of the city&#39;s actual neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response Time Analysis</title>
      <link>/findings/response-time-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/response-time-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Model Results For more details on the specification of our model, see the Data &amp;amp; Methods tab.

Measures of Model Fit We assessed the specification of our model using a posterior predictive check, which is common in Bayesian estimation. The posterior predictive check compares the distribution of predicted response times for each MCMC draw, where each draw represents one guess of what the model coefficients could be, to the actual distribution of response times in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Symptoms</title>
      <link>/findings/covid-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/covid-indicator/</guid>
      <description>Background While we were obviously interested in identifying patterns in COVID-19 symptoms across demographic groups, time, and space, this portion of the project was also quite exploratory, as it was unclear how difficult it might be to isolate potential COVID-19 cases in a large EMS dataset.
According to the Johns Hopkins Center for Systems Science and Engineering, as of June 9, 2020 (the most current date in our data), there were 258 confirmed cases and 8 deaths in Albemarle County, and 141 confirmed cases and 3 deaths in Charlottesville City.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>