<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Symposium Presentation</title>
      <link>/findings/symposium_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/symposium_page/</guid>
      <description>While this page is optional, it probably makes sense to have one weighted at the top (see the front matter at the top of this Rmd file) that gives a general overview of the project. This could be something like the final poster while the other pages highlight more in-depth observations. Here is a general schema of what should be covered throughout your website:
Main Findings [Here you will describe the results and include important visualizations from your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>/findings/context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/context/</guid>
      <description>Demographics Given this project&#39;s focus on health equity, we first wanted to develop a better understanding of the demographic makeup of Charlottesville and Albemarle. While this information is readily available from the American Community Survey (ACS), census tracts and block groups often don&#39;t present an accurate representation of the population distribution in a town or city. We therefore used data from the ACS in Charlottesville to estimate the demographic makeup of the city&#39;s actual neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response Time Analysis</title>
      <link>/findings/response-time-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/response-time-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Model Results 
For more details on the specification of our model, see the Data &amp;amp; Methods tab.

Measures of Model Fit We assessed the specification of our model using a posterior predictive check, which is common in Bayesian estimation. The posterior predictive check compares the distribution of predicted response times for each MCMC draw (I think this needs a very brief elaboration – people may not know what is being drawn exactly) to the actual distribution of response times in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Symptoms</title>
      <link>/findings/covid-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/covid-indicator/</guid>
      <description>Background While we were obviously interested in identifying patterns in COVID-19 symptoms across demographic groups, time, and space, this portion of the project was also quite exploratory, as it was unclear how difficult it might be to isolate potential COVID-19 cases in a large EMS dataset.
According to the Johns Hopkins Center for Systems Science and Engineering, as of June 9, 2020 (the most current date in our data), there were 258 confirmed cases and 8 deaths in Albemarle County, and 141 confirmed cases and 3 deaths in Charlottesville City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/</guid>
      <description>h3, h4 { text-align: center }  Data Sources This project relied primarily on a dataset of EMS incidents in Charlottesville City and Albemarle County that spanned from the December 2016 to June 2020. These data consisted of numerous variables regularly recorded by EMS providers when responding to an incident. The variables available can be broken down into three rough categories:
 Operations  Incident date and time Unit and crew dispatched Scene location and type Response time to incident Hospital patient was delivered to  Medical  Patient symptoms (based on provider&#39;s impression and/or patient&#39;s reported complaints) Vital signs (temperature, pulse, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>h3, h4 { text-align: center } .footnotes { color:rgb(195,206,208) }  The Impact of COVID-19 on the Equitable Delivery of Emergency Medical Services 
Background In recent years, public health efforts have begun to focus increasingly on the social determinants of health as a means of understanding the prevailing health inequalities in the United States and across the world. While many of these determinants very clearly relate to population health (access to health care resources, for instance), others are more subtle in their health impacts, like residential segregation, education, and cultural values1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>.justify { text-align: justify } { box-sizing: border-box; } .column { float: left; width: 25%; } .row:after { content: &#34;&#34;; display: table; clear: both; }  UVA Data Science for the Public Good Program The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>